‪‬
Gotoh
The Departure of Flamingos from Enoshima
Penguins appear in Tama River!
They're okay in freshwater?
Recruiting part-time!
‪‬
‪憂鬱な月曜日がやって来た‬
A melancholy Monday has arrived.
Feels good to be over your cold, huh?
‪‬
‪お風邪 治ってよかったね‬
Y-Yeah...
‪あ… うん‬
Or are you happy your cold
let you miss school a few days?
‪ああ お姉ちゃんは‬
‪学校 何日も休めたから‬
‪風邪ひけたほうがよかった？‬
Not at all.
‪全然 よくないよ‬
‪なんで～？‬
How come?
‪いっつも‬
‪休みたいって言ってるじゃん‬
You always say you wanna stay home...
I don't like going to school,
‪学校行くのは嫌だけど‬
‪私みたいな人間は‬
‪１日行かなかっただけで‬
but for someone like me,
even one day of failing to attend class
‪クラスのみんなから‬
‪存在を忘れられてしまうんだよ‬
puts me in risk of being
forgotten by my classmates.
‪ふ～ん‬
‪お姉ちゃんって クソめんどいね‬
Guess you're a real pain
in your own ass, Sis!
‪ワン！‬
Oh, and Mom says it's time to eat!
‪‬
‪あっ お母さんが ご飯だって‬
‪ええ そうです‬
Yes, it's true.
I could burst from the sheer volume
of nuisance I inflict upon myself.
‪お姉ちゃんも自分が‬
‪めんどくさくて めんどくさくて‬
‪もう破裂しそうで…‬
‪ん？‬
But wait a minute.
‪でも 待てよ‬
I joined a band, and I'm
working part-time at a club!
‪バンドして ライブハウスで‬
‪バイトまでしちゃって‬
Perhaps I've graduated from my introversion!
‪私 もう 陰キャじゃないのでは？‬
‪‬
‪よし！‬
‪もう一度 ギター持っていこ‬
Yes!
I'll take my guitar to school again.
Someone's bound to talk to me this time!
‪そしたら きっと‬
‪誰か話しかけてくれるよね？‬
‪‬
Yep. Putting the onus on
others fails once again.
‪はい‬
‪そんな他力本願で‬
‪誰も話しかけてくれるわけないよね‬
Hey, did you watch the latest Oto-Station?
I did did!
You can stream BAKWIMPS again!
‪サブスク 解禁されたね‬
‪バックウィンプズ‬
‪ハッ‬
‪もうさ‬
I've been listening to them
so much since yesterday,
‪昨日から聴き過ぎて‬
they're still playing in my head!
‪聴いてなくても‬
‪曲 聞こえるもんね‬
‪え～？　ヤバッ‬
Uh-oh!
Band talk!
‪バンドの話！‬
‪あっ！‬
‪えっ‬
‪わっ 後藤さん どうした？‬
What's up, Gotoh-san?
You hardly ever talk to anyone!
‪後藤さん‬
‪話しかけてくるなんて珍しい‬
All my preparation assumed
others would approach me first,
‪いつも‬
‪話しかけてもらう前提だったから‬
so I don't know how
to start a conversation...
‪話の振り方が…‬
‪えっ ああ…‬
I forgot.
‪忘れました…‬
In that short a time?!
‪この一瞬で？‬
It's lunchtime!
‪お昼だよ‬
‪これでよかったんだ‬
This is for the best.
‪もし ちゃんと話せてたら今頃…‬
If I'd managed to talk to them,
right about now...
‪ええ？‬
‪突然 話に入ってきたと思ったら‬
Barging into our convo like that...
Was she listening in the
whole time or something?!
‪私らの会話‬
‪盗み聞きしてたんですか？‬
‪後藤さんって‬
‪ヤバいヤツだったんだ‬
I didn't know she was such a creep!
‪うん 絶対こうなってた‬
That's definitely how it'd be!
I'll never rise above my station again.
‪もう調子に乗るのは やめよう‬
‪つつましく生きよう‬
I'll live under the radar forever!
Thank you for the meal.
‪ごちそうさまでした‬
Still... A quiet place like this
is just perfect for lunch.
‪‬
‪それにしても ここは静かで‬
‪お昼ご飯には最適だな～‬
I'm glad I found a nice spot.
‪いい場所見つけてよかった‬
It's awkward eating all alone
in the classroom.
‪教室じゃ 一人で食べにくいし‬
‪それに…‬
And once I become a popular guitarist,
I'll go on Oto-Station and say...
‪私が人気ギタリストになったとき‬
‪「&lrm;音&lrm;ステ」で…‬
What were you like in high school?
‪‬
‪高校のころとか何してたの？‬
I didn't have any friends back then.
‪学生のころは友達いなくて‬
‪学校によくある‬
I often ate lunch in a dark corner
filled with desks and janitorial supplies.
‪机とか掃除道具とか置いてある‬
‪謎スペースで‬
‪お昼ご飯 食べてました‬
I can awe people with how much
I've changed! Y'know how it is...
‪‬
‪ってギャップトークできる‬
‪なんてね～　ヘヘッ ウヘヘ…‬
Karaoke was so much fun the other day!
‪‬
‪この間 カラオケ楽しかったね～‬
People!
‪人っ！‬
Kita-chan's such a great singer.
‪‬
‪喜多&lrm;ちゃん やっぱり歌うまいな～‬
I heard she played guitar in a band before she quit.
Kids, don't try this at home!
辞めちゃったけど
バンドでギターも
してたらしいよ
へえ～
Wow! Now that's musical talent!
Band?
‪バンド！‬
‪そういえば&lrm;虹夏&lrm;ちゃんが‬
Come to think of it, Nijika-chan was talking
about wanting a new guitar-slash-vocalist...
‪新しいギターボーカルが欲しい‬
‪って言ってた‬
Since my cold kept me from
working for a few days,
‪この前のバイトも‬
‪風邪ひいて休んじゃったし‬
I must find a guitar-slash-vocalist
to prove my commitment to Kessoku Band!
Kessoku Band
Now Recruiting Guitar/Vocalist
Even newbies can come and learn!
Please!!
Please contact STARRY staff
‪私も 結束バンドに貢献するために‬
‪ギターボーカル探しを！‬
But the thought of going up
to a total stranger...
‪でも 初対面の人に‬
‪話しかけるなんて…‬
‪あっ 喜多ちゃ～ん‬
Kita-chan!
Heya!
‪やっほ～‬
I'm super sorry, but I have
a huge favor to ask...
‪‬
‪めっちゃ ごめんだけど…‬
What kind of girl is she?
‪一体 どんな子なんだろ‬
What is it?
‪どうしたの？‬
‪うわっ！‬
Would you mind pitching in at
our basketball game next week?
‪えっ かわいい！‬
She's pretty!
Hey, sure thing!
She's super nice!
Kids, don't try this at home!
絶対 いい子だ！
Maybe I'll land a three-pointer!
かわいくて
運動ができて
She's pretty, and athletic, and popular,
人望もあって
Awesome! Thanks!
そのうえギターまで
弾けるなんて
and she plays the guitar...
I'm supposed to issue an
invitation to someone like her?!
‪そんな子を私が勧誘できるの～？‬
‪というか アイデンティティが…‬
In fact, my identity...
My entire identity is crumbling!
‪私のアイデンティティが‬
‪崩壊する！‬
Identity
Pwip.
‪ペチョ‬
‪ん？　なんの音？‬
What was that sound?
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#3 Be Right There
‪うう…‬
‪頑張って教室まで‬
‪来たはいいものの‬
I worked up the courage
to arrive at her classroom,
‪まだ心の準備が…‬
but my mental fortitude lags behind...
‪２組の後藤さんだよね？‬
You're Gotoh-san from Class 2, right?
‪ひいっ‬
‪えっ 私の名前 知っ…‬
Sh-She knows my n—
Are you looking for someone in here?
‪‬
‪ねえ 誰かに用事でもあるの？‬
‪あっあっ あっあっ…‬
‪‬
‪い… 言うんだ ひとり！‬
S-Say it, Hitori!
Band Is Looking For
A Guitar/Vocalist
"My band is looking for a guitar-slash-
vocalist. Would you be interested?"
‪“バンドのギターボーカルを‬
‪探していて”‬
‪“うちのバンドに‬
‪興味ないですか！”‬
‪‬
Ba! Gui! Vo!
‪バ！　ギ！　ボ！‬
Ba
Gui
Vo
She became a human beatbox!
‪‬
‪突然のヒューマンビートボックス！‬
‪あっ ああ…‬
‪えっと…‬
Er...
Bam-chika-boom-chika...
bam-chika-boom-chika...
‪ぶんつく ぱーつく‬
‪つくつく ぱーつく…‬
I... I'm so sorry!
‪す… すみませ～ん！‬
W-Wait!
‪あっ ちょっと！‬
‪ああ…‬
Two more additions to
my dark past in one day.
‪一日で２つも‬
‪黒歴史を更新してしまった‬
‪‬
Lend me your ears.
‪聴いてください‬
This is my new song: Double Dark Past,
Bocchi Acoustic Version.
‪新曲“ダブル黒歴史‬
‪ぼっち弾き語り&lrm;version&lrm;”‬
‪‬
Melancholy days, multiplying traumas
‪♪ 憂鬱な日々増えていくトラウマ‬
‪♪ いらない私の負の遺産‬
Wanna ditch this negative legacy I carry...
‪♪ 思い出しては ひっそり泣いてる‬
The memories bring soft,
secret tears to my eyes
Mourning my past, so many dark mornings
‪♪ 暗いcry私の歴史‬
Wishing, someday,
to just laugh it all away...
‪♪ いつか笑い飛ばせたら‬
‪　　　　　　　　いいのにな～‬
‪ううっ… 忘れたい‬
Begone, memories...
‪えっ すご～い！‬
That was awesome!
‪うわあ！‬
K-Kita-san?!
‪きっ… 喜多さん！　いつの間に？‬
How long have you...
I got so worried when you ran off like that,
‪突然逃げちゃうから‬
‪どうしたのかと思ったら‬
but that was incredible!
‪えっ 感動！‬
‪後藤さん ギターうまいのね‬
You're amazing at guitar, Gotoh-san!
‪あっ えっ…‬
That song you were playing
had me totally enraptured!
‪さっきの演奏‬
‪すごく惹きつけられるっていうか‬
‪‬
‪た… たくさん褒めてくれる！‬
She's saying nice things about me!
What a nice person!
‪いい人！‬
Are you in a band?
‪バンドでもしてるの？‬
K-Kind of...
‪あっ 一応 はい‬
‪ねえ ほかにも何か弾けるの？‬
‪弾いて‬
Hey, can you play other stuff? I wanna hear!
Kit-aura
‪よ… 陽キャオーラが‬
‪まぶしすぎて直視できない！‬
The extrovert aura... It's so powerful,
I can't look straight at her!
Oh, and you were trying to talk
to someone earlier, right?
‪あっ その前に さっき‬
‪何か用事あったんじゃないの？‬
Th-This is my chance to invite her!
‪‬
‪こ… これは勧誘チャンス‬
W-Well, our band is actually
looking for a guitar-slash-vocalist,
‪あっ 今 自分のバンドの‬
‪ギターボーカルを探してて‬
‪え～と その 喜多さん‬
‪ギター弾けるって聞いたので‬
and I heard you played guitar, so...
Oh, so that's why.
‪ああ そっか～‬
‪あっ あれ？‬
H-Huh?
I'm sorry, Gotoh-san.
‪ごめんね 後藤さん‬
‪私 そのバンドには入れない‬
I can't join your band.
O-Oh, but...
‪あっ いや えっと…‬
I'm kind of a nerd, but the others are cool!
‪私は暗いけど‬
‪ほかのメンバーは明るくて…‬
Oh, it's not a problem with you or anything.
‪いや 後藤さんが嫌とかじゃなくて‬
They're holding a barbecue next weekend!
Meat!
‪週末は みんなでバーベキュー！‬
They host a sports meet every six months!
‪半年に一度の球技大会！‬
They party in limousines after every gig!
This is the life!
‪ライブの打ち上げはリムジンだし‬
They do so much cool stuff!
‪行事 盛りだくさんで…‬
I don't want a band that parties that hard...
‪‬
‪そんなパリピバンド 嫌なんだけど‬
And... And...
‪えっと えっと…‬
The truth is, I can't
actually play guitar at all.
‪その 正直に言うと 私‬
‪ギター 全く弾けないのね‬
‪えっ‬
I was in another band not long ago.
‪‬
‪前 ちょっといたバンドもね‬
I lied when I joined because
I wanted to get close to my senpai.
‪先輩目当てで 弾けるって‬
‪ウソついて入っちゃったというか‬
But the whole thing was just
beyond me, so I ran away.
‪けど 結局 何ひとつ 分からなくて‬
‪逃げちゃって‬
‪何ひとつ？‬
Beyond you?
Yeah.
‪うん‬
‪ギターって こっち‬
‪ジャンジャンするだけじゃないのね‬
There's more to playing than just
this strum-strum stuff, right?
‪うえっ？‬
I'd figured this wooden stick part
was just for decoration!
‪この木の棒 飾りかと思ってた‬
It's way too hard for someone
to learn on their own.
‪初心者が一人で始めるには‬
‪難しすぎるのよね‬
‪メジャーコード？　マイナー？‬
‪野球の話？‬
"Major chords"? "Minor"?
What is this, baseball?
‪‬
‪分からないの次元が違いすぎる！‬
Her non-comprehension
is on a whole other level!
‪後藤さんは‬
‪誰かに教えてもらったの？　ギター‬
Did someone teach you to play, Gotoh-san?
N-No, I mostly taught myself...
‪あっ い… いや ほとんど独学で‬
What?! Really? That's awesome!
‪‬
‪ええっ ホント？　すごい！‬
It's not that great...
‪いや～ 全然　ウヘッ ウヘヘ…‬
‪そうだ！‬
‪後藤さん ギター教えてくれない？‬
I know! Will you teach me to play, Gotoh-san?
‪私の先生になって‬
You can be my teacher!
‪うえっ！‬
You're so brilliant, I just know
you'll get me through it!
‪こんな うまい後藤さんが‬
‪教えてくれるなら‬
‪頑張れる気がするかも！‬
Oh, shucks...
‪あっ やっ ウヘヘヘ‬
I want to learn to play properly,
‪今度こそ ちゃんと‬
‪ギター弾けるようになって‬
‪前のバンドの先輩たちに‬
‪謝りに行きたい‬
go back to my old band, and apologize!
So, when can you teach me?
‪ねえ いつ‬
‪教えてもらえるかしら？‬
After class, maybe?
‪放課後とか？‬
‪あっ 私 放課後は‬
‪ライブハウスでバイトが…‬
I-I've got a job at a club after class...
‪うっ！‬
Then after work, maybe?!
‪‬
‪じゃあ バイトのあとでいいから！‬
Is there a studio next door?
We can do it there!
‪隣にスタジオとかない？‬
‪そこでお願い！‬
‪あわ… あ… ああ…‬
Oh... Oh...
V-Very well.
‪わ… 分かりました…‬
Really? Thanks!
Why am I so stupid?! Say no, girl!
‪ホント？　ありがとう！‬
‪私のバカ～ 断れ～‬
Can we start right away?
‪今日 早速行ってもいい？‬
C-Certainly...
‪あっ は… はい‬
Crap, crap, crap, crap, crap!
‪‬
‪ヤバいヤバい ヤバいヤバい ヤバい‬
I've gotta get the girls
to act like party people!
‪虹夏ちゃんたちにパリピな感じに‬
‪偽装してもらわないと！‬
‪‬
‪ん？　ぼっちちゃんからだ‬
It's from Bocchi-chan.
I'm sorry!
‪すみません…‬
Please come to work today blaring EDM and
dancing around with energy drinks on hand!
‪ＥＤＭ ガンガンかけて‬
‪リョウさんと‬
‪エナジードリンク片手に‬
‪踊り狂いながら‬
‪バイトしててください‬
What in the world?
‪なんだ これ？‬
‪さあ‬
Beats me.
Oh... You work in Shimo-Kitazawa?
‪‬
‪バイト先って下北沢だったのね‬
‪あっ 来たことあるんですか？‬
Y-You've been?
My last band was in Shimo-Kita,
‪私の前のバンド 下北系だったから‬
and its members lived in the area, so...
‪それに メンバーの先輩たちが‬
‪ここに住んでて…‬
R-Really?
‪そうなんですね‬
Hang on!
‪ちょっと 後藤さんが後ろだと‬
‪道 分からないじゃない‬
You can't walk behind me!
I don't know the way!
‪すみません‬
‪この街 まだ慣れなくて‬
I'm sorry. I'm still not
used to being here...
I'm so embarrassed!
‪恥ずかしい～‬
I'm the one embarrassed here!
‪‬
‪こっちのほうが恥ずかしいって！‬
W-We're almost there.
あっ もうすぐなんで
It's a place called Starry.
場所は
スターリーって所です
Nijika-chan and Ryo-san
will already be there...
そこに虹夏ちゃんと
リョウさんが
もういるはず…
‪えっ！‬
‪うぐっ‬
‪えっ？‬
I'm sorry. I can't go.
‪‬
‪ごめんね　私 やっぱり帰る‬
‪えっ なんで…‬
How come?
‪ぶうっ‬
I'm sorry.
ごめん
理由は言えないけど
I can't tell you why,
but that's the one place I can't go!
そこには
どうしても行けない
ここに来たことは
絶対に
And you can never tell those people I was h—
その人たちには
言わな…
‪おっ ぼっちちゃ～ん！‬
Bocchi-chan!
‪ぐわっ‬
Your instructions were super weird,
but I bought energy drinks like you asked!
‪よく分かんないけど‬
‪エナドリたくさん買ってきたよ～‬
‪って… あっ！‬
The runaway guitarist!
‪逃げたギター！‬
‪うえっ！‬
‪あひいい～‬
‪あああ…‬
‪逃げたギター？‬
Runaway... guitarist?
Kita-chan, what are you doing here?
‪喜多ちゃん なんで ここに？‬
W-W-Well, I...
‪あっ ああ… あの私…‬
Eh?
‪あれ？‬
‪あっ‬
‪あっ あ…‬
Forgive my prior discourtesy!
I'll do anything to make up for it!
‪なんでもしますから‬
‪あの日の無礼をお許しください！‬
‪どうぞ 私を‬
‪めちゃくちゃにしてください！‬
I give you permission to rough me up good!
‪おお～‬
Shh! You're gonna give people the wrong idea!
‪‬
‪誤解を生みそうな発言 やめて！‬
What?
‪ええ～っ！‬
So you couldn't play guitar, Kita-chan?
‪喜多ちゃん‬
‪ギター弾けなかったの？‬
‪はい‬
Nope.
And that's why you always ditched practice?
‪だから 合わせの練習‬
‪かたくなに避けてたんだね‬
Yeah...
Poor Kita-san seems so uncomfortable...
‪喜多さん 気まずそう‬
‪な… 何か‬
‪気の利いたことを言えれば…‬
I-If only I could think of
something nice to say.
We were worried when we didn't hear from you.
‪突然 音信不通になったから‬
‪心配してた‬
Ryo-san, so smooth!
Senpai!
‪先輩！‬
‪リョウさん さすが！‬
I assumed you were dead, so I've been
lighting incense for you every day.
‪死んだかと思って‬
‪最近は毎日 お線香あげてた‬
‪南無…‬
RIP.
‪いや 勝手に殺さないで‬
That's a pretty wild assumption...
Um... You aren't angry?
‪あの 怒らないんですか？‬
I sorta blame ourselves
for not catching on sooner.
‪気付かなかった あたしたちにも‬
‪問題あるし‬
‪それに‬
‪あの日は なんとかなったしね‬
Besides...
We managed to work it out anyway!
‪あっ‬
‪で… でも それじゃあ‬
‪私の気が収まりません！‬
S-Still, I feel too awful!
‪何か罪滅ぼしさせてください‬
Please, let me make it up to you!
I'm not sure how...
‪そんなこと言われてもな～‬
How about you help out today at the club?
‪じゃあ 今日一日‬
‪ライブハウス手伝ってくんない？‬
‪忙しくなりそうだから‬
It's gonna be a busy night.
‪そ… それだけじゃ…‬
Th-That can't be enough...
‪いや 十分助かるよ‬
‪よろしくね！‬
No, that'd be a huge help!
Please join us!
If you'd like...
‪私でよければ‬
I'm so glad they worked it out...
‪‬
‪よ… よかった　問題解決して‬
So, go over there and get changed.
‪‬
‪んじゃ ちょっと こっちで着替えて‬
Changed?
‪着替え？‬
‪‬
Why does Manager have that outfit?
‪店長さん‬
‪なんで あんな服 持ってるんだろ‬
She's pretty darn good for a fill-in worker.
‪‬
‪あいつ 臨時なのに使えるなあ‬
‪えっ？‬
Yeah, Kita-chan knows what she's doing!
‪ホント！‬
‪喜多ちゃん 手際いいね～‬
Sh-She really does!
‪‬
‪た… 確かに！　あわわ…‬
She'll give me extra time to slack off.
‪惰眠をむさぼる時間まで‬
‪できてしまった‬
I'll take it out of your pay.
‪時給から引いとくな‬
‪くんくん‬
You smell good, Kita-san.
‪喜多さん いいにおいしますね‬
‪エヘッ ありがとうございます‬
Thank you so much!
Maybe it's the shampoo? It's my favorite!
Sh-She's never said my name before!
‪わ… 私‬
‪名前呼ばれたことないのに！‬
‪あっ 喜多ちゃん 愛想いいし‬
‪受付も覚えてみる？‬
You're pretty outgoing,
Kita-chan. Wanna try reception?
‪教えるね‬
I'll teach you!
Okay!
‪はい！‬
And the job they've never trusted me with!
‪‬
‪私の任されていない仕事まで？‬
‪ドリンク代 500円です‬
500 yen for a drink ticket!
‪今日は どのバンドを‬
‪見に来られましたか？‬
What band did you come to see today?
Take a flyer, if you like!
‪フライヤーも よかったら どうぞ‬
Say, not bad at all!
‪喜多ちゃん うまいねえ‬
I love interacting with people!
‪私 人と関わるの大好きなんです‬
Ryo always handles reception,
‪いつも受付は リョウなんだけど‬
‪目が死んでて困るんだよね～‬
but her dead eyes are kind of a problem...
‪無表情 怖くない？‬
And her poker face can be scary.
Ryo-senpai looks fine just the way she is!
‪リョウ先輩は‬
‪あの顔がいいんですよ‬
Trash
Recyclables
Kita Kita
‪‬
‪ぼっち そんな所で何してる？‬
Bocchi. What are you doing down there?
‪あっ‬
‪アイデンティティの喪失中です‬
Losing my identity.
Now, lend me your ears. This is...
‪では 聴いてください‬
"The Elegy of the Part-Time Worker Who Lost
Her Identity to the Just-Arrived Newbie."
‪“その日入った新人より使えない‬
‪ダメバイトのエレジー”‬
‪‬
‪♪ ランラララン‬
‪♪ ランランランラン ラン ラン‬
‪♪ ランララ ラララ ラ…‬
Thanks for watching,
everyone!
Illustration by Aki Hamaji
短い間だったけど
We haven't known each other long,
but I enjoyed the precious
time we spent together.
貴重な体験できて
楽しかったです
Bocchi-chan! Bocchi-chan!
‪ぼっちちゃん ぼっちちゃん‬
Teach Kita-chan how to do the drinks!
‪喜多ちゃんに‬
‪ドリンク教えたげてよ‬
R-Right!
‪はっ はい！‬
‪名誉挽回のチャンス！‬
Now's my chance to restore my good name!
‪‬
‪うっ…‬
‪あっ 無理～‬
I can't do it!
‪見られてると緊張する～‬
I get nervous when I'm being watched!
‪アハハ ヘへ… ハハ…‬
Sploosh
Splooosh
Sploooosh
Splooooosh
‪わああ～！‬
‪へへヘヘ…‬
Sploooooosh
You okay?
‪大丈夫？‬
I think I get the idea,
so you can rest a while.
‪大体 分かったから‬
‪後藤さん もう休んでて‬
Please forgive my arrogance...
‪イキって すみません‬
I'm just glad you
weren't seriously hurt.
‪よかった 大事にならなくて‬
Th-Thank yo...
‪あっ ありがとうございま…‬
What?
‪あれ？‬
Her fingertips...
‪この指先…‬
Gotoh-san, what made you want to join a band?
‪後藤さんって なんで‬
‪バンド始めようと思ったの？‬
‪え？‬
It's an indoor activity where
you can be flashy and cool...
‪インドア趣味なのに‬
‪派手で かっこいいし‬
And I wanna be popular...
‪人気者になれるし‬
My motives are excessively impure!
‪動機が全部 不純すぎる‬
W-World peace... I want to
work toward world peace.
‪あっ 世界平和…‬
‪世界平和を伝えたくて…‬
How conscientious!
‪意識高いのね～‬
Tickets go on sale at 5 pm
Kessoku Band
Now Recruiting Guitar/Vocalist
Even newbies can come and learn!
Please!!
Please contact STARRY staff
Here's your cola!
‪はい こちら コーラです‬
Um, so the senpai you
wanted to get closer to...
‪あっ あの もしかして‬
‪喜多さんの言ってた‬
‪憧れの先輩って…‬
‪うん‬
Yeah.
‪リョウ先輩‬
It's Ryo-senpai.
‪どうぞ～‬
Here ya go.
‪私は後藤さんと違って‬
‪不純なんだけど‬
Unlike you, I have very impure motives.
I saw Senpai playing on the street,
‪先輩の路上ライブ見て‬
‪ひと目ぼれしたの‬
and fell head-over-heels for her.
Ryo-san was in another band, too?
‪リョウさん‬
‪ほかのバンドもしてたんだ‬
Her above-it-all attitude, her unisex look...
‪ちょっと浮世離れしてる雰囲気とか‬
‪ユニセックスな見た目とか‬
‪もう 何もかも キャ～って感じで‬
It all makes me squee!
"Squee"?
‪“キャ～”？‬
And she just looks so right
holding an instrument!
‪そして 何より 楽器が様になってて‬
‪あっ それは分かります‬
Oh, I know what you mean!
‪わ… 私が持つと どうしても‬
‪楽器に持たされてる感が…‬
Wh-When I hold mine, it looks more
like the instrument's holding me.
‪そう！‬
‪楽器が本体みたいになっちゃう‬
Right? You end up like
an appendage to the instrument.
I wonder how that happens?
‪‬
‪あっ なんか急に親近感が‬
It's like we're best
buddies all of a sudden...
That's one thing about Ryo-senpai that—
Um, can I get a cassis orange?
‪あの～ カシオレください‬
‪はい！　少々お待ちください‬
Right! Coming right up!
‪グッバイ親近感‬
‪調子乗って すみません‬
Bye-bye, buddies!
I'll know my place next time...
‪‬
‪演奏聴いてから リョウ先輩の活動‬
‪ずっと追ってたんだけど‬
After I heard her play,
I followed Ryo-san's activities for a while,
‪前のバンド 突然 抜けちゃって‬
and she dropped out of her
last band pretty suddenly.
‪へっ へえ～‬
H-Huh...
Then I found out she was
recruiting for Kessoku Band,
‪そのあと 結束バンドの‬
‪メンバー募集を知って‬
‪思わず やりたいって言っちゃって‬
and without thinking, I said I'd do it.
‪‬
‪す… すごい行動力　これが陽キャ‬
S-Such initiative! Extroversion abounds!
‪だって バンドって‬
‪第２の家族って感じしない？‬
A band is like your second family, you know?
‪家族？‬
Family?
Yeah, you spend more time with them
than with your actual family,
‪うん‬
‪本当の家族以上に‬
‪ずっと 一緒にいて‬
and you're all chasing the same dream...
‪みんなで同じ夢を追って‬
‪友達とか恋人を超越した‬
‪不思議な存在な気がして‬
It's a mysterious relationship,
closer than friends or significant others.
I've never done clubs or anything similar,
‪部活とか 何もしてこなかったし‬
so I've always wanted to be part of that.
‪そういうのに憧れてたんだ‬
I get you.
‪分かるなあ‬
‪私も ずっと憧れてたから‬
I always wanted it too...
‪そう 私は結束バンドに入って‬
‪先輩の娘になりたかったの！‬
Yes... I wanted to join Kessoku Band
and become Senpai's girl!
‪ん？‬
‪友達より深く！‬
So much deeper and more
intimate than friendship!
‪密に！‬
Wait. Is Kita-san kind of not-okay?
‪あれ？‬
‪喜多さんって 結構ヤバい人？‬
‪まあ だからこそ‬
‪バンドには もう入らないけどね‬
But that's all the more reason
I can't join the band now.
‪えっ？‬
I flaked out once already.
I'm too irresponsible.
‪一度 逃げ出した私みたいな‬
‪無責任な人間はダメよ‬
I don't deserve to be in the band.
‪バンドなんてしちゃ‬
Tickets go on sale at 5 pm
‪じゃあ お疲れ‬
‪今日は もう帰っていいよ‬
Okay, good work, all. Feel free to head home.
Thanks for having us!
‪お疲れさまでした‬
Thank you for having us...
‪お疲れさまです‬
‪あっ‬
Thanks for everything today.
‪今日は ありがとうございました‬
‪これからもバンド活動‬
‪頑張ってください‬
Good luck with your band!
I'll keep rooting for you!
‪陰ながら応援してます‬
Goodbye!
‪それでは…‬
H-Hey...
‪やっ あっ あの！‬
‪えっ？‬
‪ひぎゃっ！‬
‪ぼっちちゃん！‬
Bocchi-chan?!
‪ああ…‬
Are you all right, Gotoh-san?
‪後藤さん 大丈夫？‬
‪あっ もしかして まだ私のことを…‬
You're not still worried about me, are you?
‪ごめんね　さっき言ったとおり‬
I'm sorry.
Like I said before,
I can't join Kessoku Band.
‪私 結束バンドには入れないわ‬
I can't play guitar,
and I already flaked out once...
‪ギター弾けないし‬
‪一度 逃げ出した人間だし‬
I... I... I...
‪わ… わわ…‬
‪え？‬
I also ran away before the concert.
‪‬
‪わ… 私もライブ前に逃げ出して‬
I hid in a trash can, and...
‪ゴミ箱に隠れて‬
‪あっ あああ… あと…‬
A-A-And also...
Let's get you up, Bocchi-chan.
‪ぼっちちゃん 起こすよ‬
One, two...
‪せ～の よいしょ‬
Here we go!
K-Kita-san, your left hand...
‪き… 喜多さんの左手‬
‪ゆ… 指の先の皮が硬くて‬
Y-You had calluses on your fingertips.
I... I th-think...
‪そっ それは…‬
‪かなりギター 練習してないと‬
‪ならない‬
You'd have to be practicing
the guitar pretty hard for that.
‪うん うん‬
Y-Yeah!
‪あ…‬
Kita-chan, we'd love to have you
rocking out with us in Kessoku Band!
‪喜多ちゃんも これから結束バンド‬
‪一緒に盛り上げてほしいな‬
‪なんで 私に そんな…‬
Why would you let me...
え？　だって
Because if you hadn't flaked out,
we'd never have met Bocchi-chan!
喜多ちゃんが
逃げ出してなかったら
ぼっちちゃんとも
会えてなかったよ？
Y-Yeah!
うん うん！
‪う…‬
I've always wanted to have a band,
‪あたしも ずっと‬
‪バンドやりたかったからさ‬
so I get how it feels intimidating
and aspirational at the same time.
‪引け目感じちゃうのも‬
‪でも まだ憧れちゃうのも‬
‪気持ち分かるんだよね‬
S-So do I!
‪わっ… 私もです！‬
‪あっ‬
‪あっ ご… ごめんなさい‬
‪思ってたより声出ちゃって‬
S-Sorry. That came out
louder than I expected.
You'd be happy to have her too, right, Ryo?
‪リョウも‬
‪戻ってきてくれたら うれしいよね‬
I'll only have to pay one-quarter
of the studio and quota fees.
‪スタジオ代もノルマも４分割‬
‪素直な言い方しなよ～‬
Be a little less honest, would you?
‪あっ…‬
I can be part of Senpai's quota!
‪先輩分のノルマ 貢ぎたい！‬
So much for that healthy
moving-on thing, I guess...
‪ただれた関係が‬
‪爆誕しそうなんだけど‬
But I still can't play the guitar...
‪でも 私 ギター弾けないし‬
That's okay!
‪大丈夫！‬
‪ぼっちちゃんが先生してくれるよ‬
Bocchi-chan will teach you!
Eh?
‪え？‬
Yeah, yeah.
‪うん うん‬
‪ええっ？‬
Ehh?
‪いいの？‬
You will?
Y-Yes!
‪あっ はい！‬
I can't exactly turn her down now!
‪‬
‪この流れ 断れるわけない！‬
‪うっ… ありがとう‬
Thank you.
I'll work really hard to
play guitar in Kessoku Band!
‪私 頑張る‬
‪結束バンドのギターとして‬
‪フフッ‬
‪あっ でも 先輩たち‬
Oh, but you should probably give up
that party lifestyle of yours...
‪今のパリピバンド路線は‬
‪やめたほうがいいですよ‬
You're dancing like mad
every night, right?
‪毎晩 踊り狂ってるんですよね？‬
Where'd you hear that?!
‪それ どこ情報？‬
I'm glad it's all mended.
‪‬
‪元どおりになれて よかった‬
It came out like a mess, but I'm glad
I stopped Kita-san from leaving.
‪グダグダだったけど‬
‪喜多さんを引き止めようとして‬
‪よかった‬
I worked really hard!
‪私 頑張った！‬
‪‬
‪あっ じゃあ お先に失礼します‬
Well, I gotta head out now...
Bocchi-chan, don't go!
‪ああ～ ぼっちちゃん 待ってよ！‬
You're today's MVP!
‪今日一番の功労者なのに‬
‪あっ えっ？‬
You're the reason we're back together.
‪ぼっちのおかげで復活できた‬
Thank you, Gotoh-san!
‪後藤さん ありがとう‬
Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me
‪あっ いや 私なんか全然‬
‪大したことなんて ウヘヘ…‬
Gosh, well, it was nothing,
really, honestly...
‪‬
‪絶対 大したことしたと思ってる‬
It obviously wasn't nothing for you.
‪‬
‪後藤さん すぐ顔に出るのね‬
Gotoh-san wears her heart on her sleeve.
‪でも 私 いくら練習しても‬
‪本当にギター弾けなかったの‬
But I practiced for so long, and yet
I never really learned how to play guitar.
‪なんか‬
‪ボンボンって低い音がして…‬
It just made this quiet 'bum-bum' sound.
Y-You're sure it wasn't a bass?
‪‬
‪えっ そ… それ ベースじゃ…‬
‪私 そこまで無知じゃないって‬
Hey, I'm not that ignorant!
‪ベースって弦が４本のやつでしょ？‬
A bass has four strings, right?
See? It's got the full six strings!
‪ほ～ら ちゃんと６本あるでしょ？‬
‪‬
‪げ… 弦が６本のとかもあります‬
S-Some do have six strings...
That's a six-string bass.
‪それ 多弦ベース‬
‪んっ！‬
‪おっ…‬
‪んっ？‬
‪がっ！‬
‪あ… あひゅん‬
K-Kita-san!
‪き… 喜多さん！‬
‪‬
‪お父さんに お小遣いとお年玉‬
It cost me two years'
advance allowance from my dad,
not to mention my New Year's money...
‪２年分 前借りしたのに‬
Kita-chan!
‪喜多ちゃ～ん！‬
And so, Kessoku Band officially
had all their members.
‪こうして 結束バンドは‬
‪晴れてメンバーが‬
‪勢ぞろいしたのでした‬
‪もう嫌～っ！‬
No more!
‪私 ギター辞めます‬
I hereby quit the guitar!
What? Are we breaking up already?
‪え？　もう解散の危機？‬
Is this one defective too?
‪ねえ… これ もしかして‬
‪不良品？　またベース？‬
Did I get another bass?
‪‬
‪ま… 間違いなくギターです‬
N-No, that's definitely a guitar...
I'm sorry I whine so much.
‪ごめんなさいね　私 弱音ばっかり‬
‪後藤さんには 放課後や昼休みに‬
‪ギター教えてもらってるのに‬
I know you're giving up your time after
class and during lunch to teach me...
H-Hey, it's not...
‪あっ やっ…‬
With Ryo-senpai lending me this guitar,
and everyone helping... I have to do my best.
‪‬
‪リョウ先輩もギター貸してくれたし‬
‪みんなに助けてもらった分‬
‪頑張らなきゃ‬
‪け… けど 本当によかったですね‬
B-But I really am glad... that Ryo-san
b-bought that bass off of you...
‪リョウさんが‬
‪ベ… ベース買い取ってくれて‬
‪うん　でも 渡されるときに…‬
Yeah.
But when she gave me the money...
This is the last of my money,
so I'll be eating weeds from now on.
‪これで 私は‬
‪所持金が底をついたので‬
‪草を食べて生きていきます‬
‪あれ 冗談よね？‬
That was a joke, right?
‪本気な気がする‬
She might have been serious!
Oh, come on...
‪あっ また もう！‬
‪うまく押さえられない‬
This one's so hard to hold.
The F chord is too hard!
‪Ｆコード 難しすぎる‬
‪フフッ‬
‪ああ 懐かしい‬
‪私も こんな感じだったな‬
That takes me back.
I was this way at the start, too.
‪‬
‪あっ リョウ先輩 こんにちは…‬
Ryo-senpai! Hello...
You guys're here early.
‪２人 早いね‬
Sh-She really is eating weeds!
‪‬
‪ホ… ホントに草 食べてる！‬
Senpai's so wild!
‪先輩 ワイルド！‬
‪え？‬
The tune that plays when my loneliness
and the pedal are stepped on
Tracks down my cheeks over and over again
The pounding of my loneliness
Is joined by the rhythm of the snare drum
To create a solid pulse
Someone, please remove
the distortion on my heart
And take a look inside me
Nobody can get inside my heart
But it's the kind of night
when I hope someone will
Distortion it's Motion
Once it starts, there's no stopping it
Limits can be overwritten with experience
Isn't that right?
Distortion is always like that
My heart takes off, outpacing my left brain
Toward where you are
An escort to the next note
Distortion on my day-to-day anguish
The chord I play when I'm alone at night
Is it the same for you?
I spent all those days chasing my ideal image
Play an F chord with distortion
So loud that the needle swings off the scale
#4  Jumping Girl(s)
Watch it!
‪見てください‬